come back. So in the part one of
consumer setup we have done
basic like
what I believe is if you have gone
through that video you should be able to
set up a consumer which read from the
topic that was the intention of the part
one but now in the part two we going to
go one level deeper okay and I will go
little slow and with also demo because
this is critical Our consumer is you can
say that very critical in the sense that
there are different use cases like one
consumer
reading one topic, one consumer reading
multiple topic, multiple consumer
reading multiple topic, multiple
consumer reading like one topic. There
are different use cases. So how to set
up things? Okay. And after that there
are also like exception handling and
everything. So this is something which
we have to be very much clear because
lot of things asked and while you are
working lot of work need to be done on
the consumer side.
So let's start. Till now in basic
consumer setup we have seen how to
create a consumer and how it can read
from a topic. But now you can ask what
if one consumer request to join more
than one topic because in this the basic
setup what we have set up is one
consumer reading one topic.
Okay let's say if in one topic there are
three partition.
So all three partitions are assigned to
this consumer.
So question might have come to you. What
if one consumer
request to join more than one topic? How
to do that? Multiple consumer in a group
request to join different different
topics.
Multiple consumer in a group request to
join same topic. Okay. If these three
are clear now then after if any other
possible use cases you can think of we
can easily do that. Okay, so let's
start. So just a quick recap in basic
consumer setup what we have done is very
very simple.
We have written one Kafka listener.
Okay. And in that we have provided topic
which topic this consumer need to
subscribe and the method which is
actually the business logic.
Now here we have application.property
property file in that we have provided
bootstrap server the group id this
consumer belongs to which group that we
have defined the key serializer
and the value
not serializer d serializer the key d
serializer value d serializer okay and
the default type this is only important
when your value d serializer is JSON
okay because in that time uh Kafka need
to know that okay this JSON
decentralizer
from which
JSON to which object I need to convert
to so at least it need one default okay
so we have done this basic setup and
what we have seen this before is this
flow why I'm going through this again is
because this flow is going to play a
very important role in understanding all
these three uh items which we have seen.
Okay. So quickly do a recap that what
the flow was. So when you start the
application the spring boot application
two two beans first it will set up one
is consumer factory inside this consumer
factory we have all the
application.properties properties
information regarding consumer it has
after that it create a bean of
concurrent Kafka listener container
factory and this consumer factory bean
is
put inside this one so you can say that
this is a wrapper of this consumer
factory
after that enable Kafka generally we
don't write it it's automatically added
by spring boot so what it does is it
will scan the Kafka listener annotation
And for each Kafka listener okay it make
use of this concurrent Kafka listener
container to create one Kafka listener
container bean and when this bean is
created internally it create one Kafka
consumer which keeps on doing poll.
Okay. So you can say that in simple for
each Kafka listener one Kafka consumer
is created which continuously do the
polling in a simple way.
Okay. So what exactly happened is that
let's say we have a topic order events
which has three partition P 0, P1 and
P2. So with the above basic consumer
setup what we have achieved is we have
created one consumer group with the name
order consumer hyphen group. Okay. And
we have created one consumer.
This consumer is subscribed to which
topic order events through this. Now
since we have only one consumer in this
group. If this topic has three
partition, all the three partition would
be assigned to this consumer. Okay.
So this is what we have done. Now one
more thing is
internally
when we are doing consumer.pole.
Okay. So now in this one this consumer
is assigned three partition. Now assume
that for this topic
it has three partition and let's say
partition zero leader broker is B1
partition one leader broker is B2 and
for partition two leader broker is B1
okay so broker one is leader of
partition zero and partition two and
broker two is leader of partition one
let's say now this consumer has to pull
the events from partition zero,
partition one, partition two, right?
Because since this consumer gra group
has only one consumer, it has to take
care of all the partitions.
So I told you that each Kafka consumer
has this pole loop. So let's say this is
the loop. Okay, while true and it is
continuously do the polling. Let's see.
So this is conceptual like what
happening within the pole.
So many time what we think is that
so it first go for partition zero it
fetch the data then it goes to the
partition two it fetch the events and
then partition one then it fetch the
events but no this is not how the flow
is. So what generally happen is inside
the poll if you go what happen is for
each broker. So currently there are two
brokers for each broker this consumer
has opened one connection. Okay. And on
that connection it send the fetch
request.
Okay. So this broker one is leader of
partition zero and partition two.
So this consumer send only one request
to the broker one and ask hey
send me the events for partition zero
and partition two. Okay and your fetch
request is look like hey this is the
topic this is the partition zero and
this is the offset I want to read.
Similarly for this topic this partition
this is the offset I am interested in.
So it do not create or do not send
multiple request. So for each broker
only one request is sent and whatever
the topic whatever the partition this
broker is leader of. Okay. So this
consumer ask in one request itself.
Similarly it will send one request to
the broker two and say that okay hey
broker two you are the leader of
partition one. I need to fetch data of
it. Sendmate. So it send two requests
not three.
After that broker one send the response.
broker to send the response. What it
will do is that this consumer merge the
response of all the brokers. Okay,
whatever the so this response it merges
consumer records. So now here this is
conceptually how the consumer records
looks like. So consumer records
internally has individual records like
topic order event partition P 0. So
let's say that broker one has return
partition P 0 and partition P2 data. So
partition P 0 has consumer record
consumer record let's say two. So each
event or each record you can say that
it's a consumer record which has offset
value key header information etc.
Similarly topic partition P1 it's
consumer record individual. Similarly
topic partition the consumer records. So
it create one
output after merging all the broker
output. Okay. And then it iterate over
this record individually. First this,
first this, then this, then this, then
this. Likewise.
Okay.
So this is clear in the basic setup.
What we have done is
now our first thing is how to set up one
consumer request to join more than one
topic. We have seen one consumer one
topic. Now one consumer multiple topic.
So this is the scenario. So we have a
consumer group. We have a consumer.
Now we have two topic order event and
payment event. And now this consumer has
to join or subscribe this topic. Okay.
How to do that? So generally when
consumer
subscribe to a topic which partition
will it get it is not in it's you can
say that hands it's generally you can
say that decided by an algorithm which
group coordinator might decide but it
only say that hey I am interested in
this topic. Now whichever the partition
is allotted to it, it has to take care
of it. So in this example I have just
taken that this topic has only one
partition P 0 and payments event topic
has only one partition P 0. Let's say
for simplicity we have to do this setup.
So what is the first approach? The first
approach very simple is manually taking
care of JSON to object mapping. Okay. So
now here if you see that in the first
approach in application.properties
properties
everything is same port the group okay
um this is the group the bootstrap
server this is everything same the
important is key d serializer and value
d serializer let's say key d serializer
is a string the same now
even though the producer
is
sending the value as and serialize as
JSON.
But here consumer
I am taking the value as a string
decalizer. Okay. So whatever the JSON it
will send I am taking considering as a
string for now because I want to
manually do the mapping because events
are coming from order from payment. So
this JSON
whether it has to be type cast to let's
say or do a mapping from this JSON to
order event or you can say that order
class or payment class
in which one it has to do that I will
decide manually.
So in the value d serializer the first
thing I have done put is string tree
serializer. So here now we will get as a
JSON in a string format.
Now in the Kafka listener what is our
requirement?
One consumer
multiple topics it need to subscribe
right so in the Kafka listener we can
provide a list of topic this consumer is
interested in. You know that for each
Kafka listener one consumer is created
and it has a topics. So we can provide
list like this. So here you can see that
I'm providing a list that this consumer
is interested in order events, payment
hyphen events. So it is subscribing
to this two.
Okay. And now the method
here if you see the method which I am
expecting here is consumer record the
complete. So this is your key and this
is your value. So now here if you see
in the while loop. Okay. So internally
it here it invokes the Kafka
listener method.
Okay. This is the place right for each
record. So here I am expecting the
complete consumer record itself. Hey
send me the complete record itself and
consumer record itself. I will take care
of the mapping. So I'm expecting each
consumer record and consumer record has
this two key and the value. So both are
a string is string. Key is also a string
and the value is also a string. So now
what I'm doing is this record has all
the information. record has topic
information, partition information. You
can take out the key, you can take out
the value, you can take out the header,
everything. Okay? So, I'm just checking
if order event dot equals record dot
topic. So, if topic is order event, I am
manually doing the mapping from JSON to
object. So I have auto wired the object
mapper
and just doing dot read value whatever
the value I am getting JSON convert it
map it to order.class class. Now I'm got
this else if
if record dot topic whatever the event
this record is there if its topic is
payment event I am mapping this record
value to payment class okay so manually
I am taking care of mapping JSON to
object mapping okay and remember that
when we are using a string string d
serializer you don't need default type
and itself. I already told you default
type is only required when you have a
value dializer as JSON because it has to
convert from JSON to object. But since
we have a string D serializer, it
doesn't have to convert it. So we don't
need default type. Okay. So here this is
how we can take the full responsibility
of converting or you can say that
mapping from JSON to a specific object
based on the topic.
Okay,
let's see the demo. So here I have
already cleaned everything like uh
deleted all the logs started the
controller and the broker and we can
check that any event exists. Currently
payment event also doesn't exist
also
order events also does not exist. Okay.
Now
this is the producer.
So
just to check in the producer config
it will create
a order event three partition and it
will create payment events right and
here I have one method with key
and it will
publish order hyphen events
and here I have with key hyphen payments
which publish a payment hyphen events.
Okay. So, let me and also let me see.
Nothing much, right? Yeah, this is what
so let me first start the producer.
Let me start the producer application.
So, producer application is started.
Let's see the topics are created. Order
hyphen events created and similarly
payment hyphen events also created.
Okay. three partition and two replica uh
two replicas.
Okay, cool. So producer is up and
running. Now consumer so consumer what
we are so I have created multiple
listeners. So which we will see. So the
listener which we are interested
currently is the manual mapping one. So
here if you see all other listeners one
by one we will see. So currently all uh
other listeners are commented out. All
we are interested in this listener
manual mapping we we are currently
seeing that. So Kafka listener the
topics I am interested in order events
payment hyphen events. Okay. And uh this
is the consumer record I am taking out.
If topic is order events I am man doing
manual mapping. Okay. And this your
object mapper is coming from JSON.
Similarly, if payment event, I'm doing
payment mapping and just printing out.
Okay. And let me just check properties.
In properties,
we don't need this. We don't need
default type. Very simple. Okay. And the
value decelizer we want is
a string decalizer only. We want this.
Okay.
So, I think we are good to start the
consumer application. And let me see
config everything is commented out.
Cool. So let's start the consumer
application also.
Consumer application is also started.
Now we will hit with key with key
publish order. Okay. So here let's say
order - 1. This is going to publish
order created and event publish and with
key hyphen payment is will publish
payment. So p-1 first
payment created event published. Let's
see
it successfully read consumer
successfully read.
Okay. So it printed this this one
payment and
order colon
sorry so approach one is clear right
manual so we accept it as a string and
then we take care of doing the mapping
what is the approach to auto mapping
which is very important
and before I'll show you the code how to
do that we need to understand
JSON
serializer
and
JSON
d serializer flow very very important
because this is the place where many
engineer get confused
okay and this is the place where I can
say that lot of gap exist
without that auto mapping is like would
become very tough like hey why it is
working now why it is not working like
like this kind of scenario can come
okay let's see the flow JSON dialization
flow I need to tell you but let's start
from the producer
and again one more thing when we are
talking about automapping so see this
this mapping thing right it's all comes
when we have to convert from JSON to
object when our value is JSON serializer
DS serializer If it is not JSON, if it
is a string and all then this all things
is not comes into the picture because we
don't have to convert JSON to object and
all. But in real world most of the
scenario it's always value is mostly
mostly JSON uh serializer DS serializer.
Okay, because uh it's always an object
but if it is not an uh JSON serializer
or DS serializer if it is a string it's
like this straightforward.
Maybe you don't have to do this mapping
also. Okay.
Okay. Now let's just start from the
producer at producer side during JSON
serialization
what we were doing. Okay. If you see
we you I hope you have already seen the
producer setup and producer internals.
So we have autowired Kafka template is
string and order. So this is key which
is a string and value is order. Okay,
this is the object Kafka template and
this is how we are sending the event.
Okay, this is the topic. This is your
key. This is your value
in application.properties. We have so
many properties in uh for the producer.
The main here for the over is uh
serializer. So key serializer here is
our string
string serializer and value is here we
have object so JSON serializer so value
serializer is JSON
important thing
spring.cafka.producerproperties
spring.json add type header add.type do
header is true. This is by default. We
don't have to do this is by default true
only. Okay. So I just add it here to
tell you that this is by default true.
Even though you don't write it, it's
present. And why? What is the importance
of this type header? So see the name
type header.
So since our value
is object. Okay. So type header means
when you publish an event it will add a
type id in the header which has like the
path of your class. So this order let's
say
uh this is my value right.
So it will put its path com.
EDA.producer.mmodel
dot order. Okay. So it's in the type id
field within a header. It add the class
path.
Okay. But you might be thinking, hey, in
the producer setup, okay, uh you are
saying this by default is true. So we
haven't added it. So definitely it's
true only because we haven't made it
false in producer setup and all. And all
the demo which we have seen, we have
seen that header keys uh generally like
empty. This is what we have seen till
now. Okay. But what I am saying right
now is that hey this by default is true
and whenever we are sending an object
okay means it's a JSON serializer we are
using it it add a type ID which has the
class path of the class whichever we are
using here for the value. So it should
be if you see our logs it should be like
header key type id is present it should
be like this but till now what we have
seen our header keys is empty why see I
it's not always 100% sure that producer
will always add type ID okay this is
what it says that by default type header
is true so it should add it should add a
type ID into the header which has this
class path. Okay, but it's not I would
say that 100% true. Why? And I will tell
you the specific use case. So when you
try with this
string order is specific if you specify
the exact
uh I would say that the class order
and if you try it you will see that
header type is empty but if you replace
it with string object
okay you don't specify a specific class
okay then you will notice that it will
add a type ID in the header
So it is internal to producer I would
say that but for us I would say
we have to be uh clear that okay by
default this config is true and if this
config is true and we are using JSON
serializer it will add a type ID
okay this is for now we can say that but
again I'm saying you it's not always
100% true always verify whether it is
adding or not because this is one use
case I'm telling you there could be more
use case which it might not be adding so
one use case is if you provide a direct
class it might not add like we have seen
it previously but if you replace it with
like generic object okay then you will
see that it is adding type ID
so first thing is clear that
producer
is adding the type ID. Let's set uh
let's do that. Okay. So here
in our scenario
producer let me check what
here. So send with key we have seen that
right I have object here. Okay. So if we
go what partition let me see what
partition it has published. Partition P
0. Okay. So now we can check the
partition P 0
for the payment and for for payment also
right for payment also uh partition P 0.
So we can check partition P 0 whether it
would be broker one or broker two we can
check both okay broker one we got the
data. So header key is type ID.
Similarly, we can check the order
order - events.
We can check type ID is present.
Okay. And like I have previously showed
you all the demo of the producer where
we were directly using this specific
order class, the type ID was missing.
You can test it. I have tested it. you
can also test it from your side. Uh but
with respect to the time I am saying
that uh this is the behavior you going
to see. Okay. So when you
clean everything and just try to use
order you will see that empty header ID.
Okay. Like this. But now when we are
using object the type ID is coming.
Okay. So that's why I said it's not
always 100% true that uh when it when
this config is true it will and you have
a JSON serializer it will always come.
Okay. Now let's see the consumer side
the des serializer side. So at producer
side we are saying that
type ID can come or cannot come. Okay,
only two scenarios.
So what happened at the consumer side?
So for each Kafka consumer record, for
each record means for each event we have
bytes plus header. Okay. So each event
we have header also. Header information
also comes. Okay. So what it what's the
flow? So this flow is very important.
Understand this flow because this is
where many confusion comes.
The first for each event the first it
goes to the is JSON D serializer or not.
Okay, it will check in
application.properties of consumer we
have set the value D serializer right.
So if it is only JSON then only this
flow matters otherwise this flow doesn't
even matter. I already told you this is
all specific for JSON serializer
decalizer only.
If it is a JSON d serializer. Yes. What
consumer will do? It will check is below
config true or false. So which config?
Use type header. Okay. What we are
saying that hey in the event we also get
the header do you want to use it or not?
We have a two true or false. By default
it is true but we can also make it
false.
So if you make it false where it goes
it goes to your default type config.
Okay. So if you remember in the consumer
we also have default type config. Right.
So it will use that
and then it will do decentralization
from JSON to the one which you have
provided in the default and after that
it will invoke your Kafka listener
method.
Okay. So this flow is clear right and
the default type config which I'm
talking about is here. If you open the
consumer application.properties
properties
which we have already set up
here. This is what I'm talking about
default type. Okay. So if you're not
using header
and uh it will make use of this default
type. So this class it will try to
convert your JSON to this class object
and then ultimately it invoke this Kafka
listener method.
where it goes. Yeah. So this false flow
is clear, right? When use type header is
false. But now let's say if you are not
even using this, so by default it is
true or you have specifically mentioned
true. By default it is true. So means
you have to listen to the header. Now in
the header two possibilities, right?
Type ID is present or type ID is not
present.
So if it is not present it again goes to
this only. It make use of default and do
the decentralization JSON to object
whatever the type we have defined
whatever the class path and then call
the Kafka listener method invoke
but if type ID is present
okay if type ID is present like let's
say in the type ID let's say this is
present in type ID
it's present com dotproducer dot order
hey this value
this bite let's say or this JSON you can
say
is of you need to so it you can say that
producer is sending the information this
JSON which I have created it's from
that's comproducer dot order class okay
so it has given us this information
now there are two things we can do it
will check hey mapping present yes or no
what is this mapping
So this is one configuration very
important configuration spring. Kafka
dot consumer.properties
dot spring.json.type
dot mapping type mapping type dot
mapping. So here we can have like from
two.
So from is like whatever the type ID
class path hey this from this class path
convert it to this. So you are
specifically telling to the JSON
decentralizer that
this type ID you can convert it from
this to this.
Okay. So if mapping is present
use it
decentralize from the JSON
okay and convert it to the object like
type ID from this to this. So this
object would be used here and then it
will invoke the Kafka method.
Kafka uh listener method
but what if this mapping is not present
okay or you can say that uh mapping is
present so it's a comma separated you
can have mapping right you can have so
many mapping here it's you can say that
it's a comma separated okay then after
that you can have so many so let's say
if this config is not even present or in
this uh list this type ID mapping is not
present in that scenario So what JSON
decentralizer will try to do is it will
try to decentralize JSON to object. Now
which object it will try this but there
is a security risk. Okay. What if hacker
put it's uh some fake class path
com.hacker dot order let's say.
So JSON decentralizer will try to load
this class to convert from JSON to
object. It will try to load this class.
So this is risky. That's why whenever
mapping is not present,
it will check for trusted package.
So trusted packages like this
configuration spring. Kafka
do.consumer.properties
spring.json.rusted.packages.
So you can provide a comma separated. So
this package I am trust. com do.t
producer. This package I trust means any
class within this package approve it.
Okay. So in type id what I'm getting is
com.producer.t orderer. In trusted it
will see that hey I have com.producer.
Yes this class will get approved.
Okay. Or you can also put
trusted.package equals to asteris means
approve everything.
Okay.
But if in the trusted package
this is not present com.producer dot
order is specific like if this is not
passed through from this trusted package
it will throw
illegal argument exception not in
trusted package.
But let's say that we have defined
trusted.package com.producer.
Okay. So when this class will come it
will pass through. Yes.
Now what uh JSON dieselizer will try to
do? It will try to load
this class. So now it will check class
existence consumer path or not because
see you have let's say consumer
repo. So this class com.producer.order
should be present into consumer also
right? So it should be able to load. If
it not able to load class not found
exception. If it able to load it will
convert the JSON to this object and
invoke Kafka listener method.
So go through this flow again because
this is critical because this is where
all the whatever the combination you do
one consumer multiple topic and all this
flow going to help you. Okay. And this
is where many many you can say that gaps
are present which if you understand the
flow those will get clarified.
Now this flow is clear. Let's move to
the auto mapping now. So producer is
doing what? So our producer is doing
that sending the object. So it is
sending order
order event. It is sending payment
event. Okay. And since it is object so
definitely type id is also coming in the
header
now in the consumer what is happening
keep in mind the the flow which we have
seen
so everything is same the key value
dializer is JSON now since it is JSON
dializer
I have multiple ways so one which I am
using is mapping so I'm providing the
mapping
that
specifically I'm providing. So whatever
the type ID it will so whenever this
event is published it will add a type ID
in its event. When this event is
published it will add a type ID with
also for this event. So I'm adding a
mapping comma separated.
So com.eda.producer
domodel. So this is from which is
present into type ID header. Convert it
to this one. Map it to this one. And you
can say that com.ed.consumer.
So this this class is present into
consumer class path.
Similarly com.eda.producer
when this comes map it to this one.
Okay. So this here if you can this
pojo's order and the payment is present
into consumer class path
and default you can keep it. Okay.
because uh default is required whenever
we have a JSON dializer.
Now here what I'm doing I am writing a
Kafka listener. So one consumer our
requirement was one consumer multiple
topics right? So same here nothing
difference like how we were doing
manually topic one topic two I'm
interested in
I'm reading the consumer record itself.
Okay. So here if you see a string I'm
getting this string.
Now order events I am checking equals
topic
if topic is equal order events here if
you see I don't need to do the mapping
itself I am just doing a type cast from
this value to the order that's all.
Similarly when your topic is payment
event I am not doing JSON mapping
everything that would be done by JSON
digitalizer now okay with the help of
this
all I'm doing is just type casting
record dot value to this
okay
let's
test this now
so our producer no change it is still
producing the type ID So in our consumer
we have to change now. So listener
so we don't need this listener we need a
listener
this and there is one change is that we
are using JSON dializer okay we are
using JSON dializer so this cannot be a
string
this cannot be a string it's an object
here
it's an object here so in the auto
mapping it's an object here.
So our Kafka listener one consumer
listening multiple events consumer
record key and the value value is our
JSON dializer. Okay. So and since we can
have multiple events of different type
so that's why I used object here
if topic is equals order event just type
cast it and print it out this similarly
type casted printed out this if it is
this one all good let me check
application.properties properties. Yeah,
I need to change it to
this one. JSON dializer.
So, let's use this one.
Okay, JSON dializer. I I am interested
in header. Yes, that's why I commented
out I am interested in header. Default
type is needed now because we have a
JSON digitalizer. So, default type is
needed and mapping. So we want mapping
also right. So this is the mapping for
the one which I have
okay so I have provided the mapping
also. So this is our uh different lines
right. So that's why I have added this
one.
Now here also if you see
one thing is that when you provide a
mapping you don't have to provide
trusted package okay so I think this is
clear right so many time if you see that
they say hey why you are not providing
trusted package or not so when the
mapping is present yes this trusted
package is not required so that's why
I'm not adding any trusted package here
So header is false.
We are interested in the header. Okay.
Uh value dializer is JSON dializers.
Default type we needed it but mapping is
provided. So it will never reach to the
default itself. So all good. Now let me
stop the consumer.
Okay. And also in the listener
everything is commented out right. So
this listener commented out commented
out. commented out only this our auto
mapping listener is active.
Okay, let me add double so that we know
that our properly is getting invoked. So
let me start the consumer
run.
So consumer is started. Let's publish
first order. So with key was order
- 2
and then payment hy - 2
bad request. So let's say what got
changed - 2
payment created. So here if you see that
our Kafka listener properly able to
listen it
this is very important. This flow is
very important. Right? If that is clear
after that now you will see that
everything is very simple. So now our
second thing is we want to set up
multiple consumer in a group to join
different topic. So now in a group I
have consumer one consumer two they need
to join different topic one is joining
order event one is joining payment event
approach one very simple two different
consumer application
okay like how in the basic setup we have
set up right one consumer like you
created two different application okay
that is simple okay and in the kafka
listener for one you can tell order
event for other you can tell payment
But in single application how we can do
that again very simple if you understand
this flow you know that for each Kafka
listener for each Kafka listener
one Kafka consumer object is created. If
this flow is clear you know that what
you have to do you have to create two
Kafka listeners
but I will show you with two ways. One
is type ID plus mapping. Type ID plus
mapping means producer is sending a type
ID
and consumer
is doing the mapping means it is
interested in the header and it is doing
the mapping. How to do that? Another is
header equals to fall. Consumer is not
even listening to the header. Let's say
then how to do that? Very interesting.
So let's start first very simple we have
seen the previous flow itself. So we
need two consumer
reading two different topic and we know
that one Kafka listener one Kafka
consumer. So I have created two Kafka
listener. This Kafka listener means one
consumer is subscribing to order event.
This consumer will subscribe to payment
event. Okay. So it is accepting the
value order accepting the value payment
and in application.properties properties
what we want we are doing is mapping.
Okay. So everything same group uh key
dializer is string value is object JSON
dializer. So we need default type but
here I'm providing a mapping from this
class of the producer whichever it is
coming the
type ID in the header map it to this
consumer class. Similarly this map it to
this and it works fine. This is the
exact same what we have seen. Uh but now
only here is now we have two consumer
two different topics they are listening
to.
But this one is very interesting. Now we
are because now we are reading this
flow. Now we are going to this flow
false one. Okay. Earlier we was checking
this flow true. Now in when it is false
what is the expectation? it check out
the default type config and from the
default type config it will convert JSON
to object and then invoke the Kafka
listener method.
Now I guess by now itself you know what
the problem you're going to get but yeah
let's see so first thing first two
consumer so I have created two Kafka
listener one consumer is interested or
subscribing to order event another
consumer is subscribing to payment event
and they have orders and the payment
this is the whatever the value so that
would uh like JSON to specific object
and that object is only is sending value
is only sending not the complete
consumer record.
Now in the application.properties
properties. You might be thinking that
okay everything same key dializer is
string value is JSON
so you need default type you added the
default type now here use type do header
false I'm specifically saying false
because by default is true so I'm
specifically saying false
this will not work why
so when let's say producer has published
an event
order
Consumer able to properly consume when
producer publish payment
consumer will fail. It will fail that
hey cannot convert from order to
payment. Why? I told you when you put
header equals to false read use type
header equals to false what it will make
use of is default type. Okay. So when
your producer sending the order event so
order event would be type cast to order
properly done consumer able to read it
properly. Okay. Uh decentralization work
properly when producers and payment and
consumer read this event. Since use
header type is false it will use default
type. Now what it is trying to do is
converting. Okay. It will try to dialize
this payment into order. it won't be
able to do desialization fails.
Okay. So how to resolve this?
So we need to understand the problem
first and after that solution is like
intuition.
So if you that's why I go through this
flow again and again because this flow
is where the solution lies.
The issue comes because when you start
the spring boot application you know
that two bean it created consumer
factory and the concurrent Kafka
listener container factory. Consumer
factory what it has all the properties
from the application.properties
file and in the application.property
file we also have default type. Okay. So
it also has let's say default type also.
And now this object is wrapped into this
concurrent Kafka listener container
factory.
Now
when it start scanning Kafka listener.
Okay. So what it found two two Kafka
listener one for order one for payment
event. So now for order event it will
create a consumer.
Okay. Now let's say it create a
consumer. So it create a consumer with
which what object consumer factory and
this consumer factory has what default
type this one let's say order similarly
for another Kafka listener let's say for
payment it will make use of your
consumer factory object only to create
Kafka consumer right so this consumer
factory this has what property order
only. So means same object same consumer
factory object is used to create a
consumer object for both order and
payment and that's where the issue is
because from in application.property
property we have only one way. We can
define only one default type. But if you
have multiple Kafka listener this same
default type would be for this Kafka
consumer for this Kafka consumer.
Now the question is or you can say that
the solution is that hey when we have
multiple listener they should have the
consumer factory with their own default
type. They should have a consumer
factory with their own default type.
That's the only solution I have built.
So what I have done is I've created one
configuration class at the rate
configuration.
The same thing this this two things I
now I am taking the control.
So first is I am creating order consumer
factory.
Okay. So
the parameter it accept is Kafka
properties. So here props this one dot
build consumer property. See means
whatever you have
properties defined into
application.property file that will
come. Now you can override whatever you
want. What I'm overriding value default
type. Hey use this order.class for order
consumer factory and return default
Kafka consumer factory object with this
config.
So I created a bean for
with my my logic. Similarly for payment
the same thing payment consumer factory
first load all the properties which is
present into application.properties.
Now whatever the property you got loaded
override the default type now
payment.class for the payment one. Okay.
And just create an object.
First step done this I have done created
for both now the second I told you that
concurrent we need to create this object
and within this object we have to wrap
this consumer factory that's what I'm
doing
concurrent one object bean we have to
create so one I'm creating for order
another I'm creating for payment okay so
concurrent object we are creating and
within this object I'm just wrapping up
the factory this one order consumer
factory similarly in the payment one I
am wrapping the payment consumer factory
this one that's all
that's the only thing which I have done
now only thing is during Kafka listener
I am telling topic is this and the
container factory which I have to use is
order Kafka listener factory this one
similarly for payment
the topic is payment event container
factory which have to use is payment and
Kafka listener factory this one that's
solve now header equals to false
okay now everything works smooth no
change okay let's do this demo also and
I think it would be get super clear with
this sorry I'm going little slow because
this is critical right otherwise lot of
doubt would get happen into this one
so
in the config these are the confixs one
Right. So here we have order consumer
factory.
We have
the concurrent object. Okay. So now we
have this configuration
event listener we are interested in
which one we are doing at like two
different topics right? So one we have
Kafka listener topic is this and
container factory
is order one
this one
okay and received order event and
similarly here this is payment event
container factory I have already defined
it rest all Kafka listeners are empty
okay so this is done
application.properties properties
header equals to false. This is the one
we are testing
and
we have JSON dializer. So default type
we have to provide it. But now this time
it won't impact because we have created
individual for each Kafka container. So
it's okay. But yeah we don't need
mapping.
All good now. So only thing is header
type. Use header type is false.
So let's stop the consumer and start it
again.
Okay.
So I'm publishing then event 02111
order created event publish P2111
payment created event publish it read.
Okay.
So
got the use case because many time if in
your company you have a use case that
hey producer is not sending the type ID
then
this might comes handy to you.
The last how to set up multiple consumer
in a group to join same topic. Okay, we
have seen one joining multiple. Now it's
like multiple consumer same topic. Okay,
you can only tell which topic you want
to subscribe,
which partition you will be allotted.
That is when you go with the subscribe
model, it's not in your hand. Okay.
Generally there are two model subscribe
and assign. Subscribe is something you
can say that uh mostly used. Okay. group
coordinator
has uh used the algorithm and you can
say that allot the partition to you in
the assign consumer tell hey I am
interested in this partition but the
problem is that you have to manually
then do polling and all I think that's
not my intention I've never used assign
but here if you are going with the
assign you have to manage everything
but since we are using a spring boot we
want everything to be abstracted and So
when we are using spring boot everything
is abstracted. So within abstraction it
use subscribe. Okay. But if you have to
do it by yourself you can also have a
chance to do assign. You can assign
particular partition to you. But hardly
I don't think anybody write this
framework code by themselves and do
this. So if you're using framework I
think it's all subscribe. So you it's
which partition not in your hand.
So all we have to is they subscribe to
the same topic and individual different
partitions of the same topic need to be
assigned to them. How to do that? So one
thing is
like
I'm creating consumer like how you are
doing this here Kafka consumer topic is
order event. What this will do? This
will create you know that one Kafka
listener means one consumer.
Okay. And they will subscribe to order
events.
But our requirement is we need multiple
consumers subscribe to this. Then in
application.properties
there is something called
spring.cafka.lister.conurrency
equals to whatever you want to provide 2
3 4 whatever.
So again this flow I'm coming to you.
So when you have created a bean of this
concurrent Kafka listener when this you
scan the Kafka listener for each Kafka
listener
concurrent Kafka listener container
factory you can say that creates a
consumer
but when you have defined this
configuration listener do. Concurrency
equals to three let's say. So this
configuration is or you can say that
this property is ultimately seted to
this one this bean while creation of
this bean this concurrency equals to
three set. So here if you see in the
configuration
so let's say this is concurrent one
right here I can set it has this field
factory dot concurrency
set
concurrency okay
so if you are manually creating it you
can set it like this otherwise if you
are not manually creating this beans uh
then if you are provided into the
application property this gets set into
this. Okay. And when it will create this
Kafka consumer object if it see that hey
whatever the uh by default it is one.
Okay. So if you have provided more than
one it will create that number of Kafka
consumer.
So now in this case what it will do is
that since we are provided let's say
concurrency three
okay it will not create one consumer it
will create three consumers
all reading to the this all subscribing
to this topic which partition is
allotted that group coordinator will
decide.
Got it?
So with this you can say that
part two of consumer setup is done where
we have gone one level more deeper.
Now in part three what I wanted to show
you that if you remember we have
multiple steps till step 13 in the
consumer read flow. So each step what
all the possibilities can come or you
can say the doubts can come. Okay, for
example, when you read or when you do
poll or like one example I showed you,
right? During poll,
uh if you have multiple broker, broker
one, broker two, the consumer will send
the request. So what if one broker
fails? What it didn't send the request?
So like all this possible scenario on
each step
what all thing only important one I will
go how to handle those. So all the
possible doubts and all the possible
solutions. Okay. So in the part three
that I will cover and in the part four
exception handling.
Okay. So this is also very important. So
with that our consumer would like
foolproof.
Okay. And after that we will proceed
further on different topics. But yes
this is very critical. I don't want to
skip those. But still if you have any
doubt in this topic let me know. We can
discuss further. And again sorry for
going little slow because I want this to
be super clear. Okay guys, bye.